Robert Houghwout Jackson Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- Financial Papers, 1918-1954 (Box 192-201)
  Accounts, correspondence, financial statements, income tax records, insurance papers, investment records, real estate papers, and miscellaneous lists and notes.
  Arranged by type of material.
  - Accounts (Box 192)
    - Account books
      - 1935-1943, (4 folders)
      - 1944-1948, (3 folders) (Box 193)
      - Household expenses, 1946-1952
    - Agency account, Bank of Jamestown, Jamestown, N.Y.
      - 1934-1943
      - 1944-1954 (Box 194)
    - Ledger sheets, 1920-1934
      - Office
        - A-O, (5 folders)
        - Q-Z, (3 folders) (Box 195)
      - Personal, (2 folders)
    - Office statements
  - Automobile
  - Bank of Jamestown, Jamestown, N.Y. (Box 196)
  - Contributions
  - Financial statements
  - Gift tax
  - Income tax records
    - 1918-1928, (9 folders)
    - 1929-1939, (10 folders) (Box 197)
    - 1940-1944, (7 folders) (Box 198)
    - 1945-1954, (7 folders) (Box 199)
  - Insurance papers, (1 folder) (Box 200)
  - Investments
    - Chessman correspondence re stock, Bank of Jamestown, Jamestown, N.Y.
    - Notice, reports, etc.
    - Sale of stock, Bank of Jamestown, Jamestown, N.Y.
    - Stocks and bonds
  - Invoices, law practice, 1934-1936
  - Miscellany
  - Real estate
    - Harrison Street property
    - Hickory Hill, (2 folders) (Box 201)
    - Jamestown property, Jamestown, N.Y., early deeds, etc. See also Oversize
    - Lakewood Road property
  - Riggs National Bank, Washington, D.C.
  - Safety deposit box, Bank of Jamestown, Jamestown, N.Y., 1934-1939
  - Social security tax, Stuart Loy
- Miscellany, 1822-1983 (Box 202-250)
  Appointment calendars, awards, honors, tributes, calling cards, financial papers, index card files, inventories of the collection, memorials, memorabilia, social invitations, and printed matter.
  - Appointment calendars (Box 202)
    - Jan. 1936-June 1940, (6 folders)
  - Appointment calendars (Box 203)
    - July 1940-June 1942, (5 folders)
    - July 1942-June 1945, (6 folders) (Box 204)
    - Aug. 1946-Dec. 1948, (5 folders) (Box 205)
    - Jan. 1949-Dec. 1951, (6 folders) (Box 206)
    - Jan. 1952-June 1954, (6 folders) (Box 207)
    - Oct. 1951-Dec. 1954 set no. 2, (4 folders) (Box 208)
  - Articles about Jackson, 1935-1974, (2 folders)
  - Awards, certificates, honors, and tributes
    - Nov. 1913-Sept. 1950 See also Oversize, (11 folders)
    - Oct. 1950-Dec. 1954 See also Oversize, (4 folders) (Box 209)
    - Miscellany
  - Birthday greetings and celebrations
  - "Bohemia"
  - Calling cards See Container 249
  - Clippings
    - Chronological file
      - Jan. 1919-Mar. 1937, (4 folders)
      - Mar.-Sept. 1937, (4 folders) (Box 210)
      - Oct. 1937-Jan. 1938, (4 folders) (Box 211)
      - Jan.-Feb. 1938, (4 folders) (Box 212)
      - Feb.-Nov. 1938, (6 folders) (Box 213)
      - Nov. 1938-Feb. 1939, (4 folders) (Box 214)
      - Mar.-Oct. 1939, (4 folders) (Box 215)
      - Nov. 1939-Jan. 1940, (3 folders) (Box 216)
      - Apr.-June 1945, (6 folders) (Box 217)
      - July-Aug. 1945, (4 folders) (Box 218)
      - Sept.-Dec. 1945, (4 folders) (Box 219)
      - Jan.-June 1946, (5 folders) (Box 220)
      - June 1946, (4 folders) (Box 221)
      - July-Sept. 1946, (5 folders) (Box 222)
      - Sept.-Oct. 1946, (4 folders) (Box 223)
      - Oct. 1946, (3 folders); (4 folders); (1 folders) (Box 224, Box 225, Box 226)
      - Nov.-Dec., (3 folders)
      - Jan. 1947-May 1954, (6 folders) (Box 227)
    - Supreme Court (Box 228)
      - 1944-1946, (7 folders)
      - 1947-1952, (8 folders) (Box 229)
      - 1953-1954, (2 folders) (Box 230)
    - Unsorted
      - 1910-1937, (5 folders)
      - 1938-1943, (6 folders) (Box 231)
      - 1944-1959, (9 folders) (Box 232)
      - 1960-1983, undated, (4 folders) (Box 233)
  - Estate of Robert H. Jackson
    - Correspondence files, (2 folders); (5 folders) (Box 234)
    - Legal file, (1 folder) (Box 235)
    - Miscellany
    - Receipts, vouchers, and consents
    - Sale of bonds
    - Tax returns and working papers
  - Funeral and obituaries
  - Illnesses (Box 236)
    - 1953 surgery
    - 1954 heart attack, get-well messages and replies, (2 folders)
  - Inventories of Jackson's papers
    - Catalog, 1934-194l
    - File cabinets nos. 8 and 10, and miscellaneous
    - Speeches and articles
    - Supreme Court opinions
  - Invitations, thank-you notes, regrets (Box 237)
    - Jan. 1939-Apr. 1942, (10 folders)
    - May 1942-June 1944, (10 folders) (Box 238)
    - July 1944-Dec. 1949, (8 folders) (Box 239)
    - Jan. 1950-Oct. 1954, undated, (7 folders) (Box 240)
  - Jamestown, N.Y., miscellany (Box 241)
  - Jefferson, Thomas, and William Johnson, correspondence (typescripts), 1822
  - Last will and testament and letter of intent, 1952-1954
  - Lincoln, Abraham, pages from the New York Herald, 15 Apr. 1865, and lecture by Robert G. Ingersoll, 1909
  - Mailing lists
  - Membership and identification cards and passes
  - Memorials to Jackson, 1954-1977
    - Dedication of airport terminal, Chautaugua Co., N.Y., 10 June 1973
    - Frewsburg Central School, Frewsburg, N.Y., 1955-1965
    - Justice Robert H. Jackson Lecture Series, 1960-1967
    - Memorial record book, 9 Oct. 1954
    - Miscellaneous, 1954-1977, (2 folders) (Box 242)
    - Robert H. Jackson Memorial Committee, 1964-1971
    - Supreme Court, 1954-1955, (2 folders)
    - Tenth memorial anniversary, 14 Oct. 1964 (Box 243)
  - Notes
  - Passports and baptismal certificate
  - Printed matter
  - Programs and souvenirs, 1912-1954, (2 folders)
  - Quotations, excerpts, statements, and poems of others
  - Researcher's notes on the Nuremberg War Crimes Trial
  - School papers (Box 244)
    - Academic records, 1898-1912
    - Miscellany
    - Speeches and debate papers, 1907-1910
  - Tea at Corcoran Art Gallery, Washington, D.C., honoring exhibition of Jackson's portrait, 5 Oct. 1942
  - Trips
    - 1924
      - American Bar Association meeting, London, England, (3 folders); (1 folder) (Box 245)
      - Europe, (2 folders)
    - 1935, Stockholm, Sweden
    - 1945-1946
      - Athens, Greece
      - Austria
      - Belgium
      - Berlin, Germany (Box 246)
      - Christmas, 1945
      - Czechoslovakia
      - Denmark
      - Egypt
      - Garmisch and Dachau, Germany
      - London, England
      - Norway
      - Nuremberg, Germany, (2 folders) (Box 247)
      - Paris, France
      - Rome, Italy
      - Sweden
  - Willard, Mary R.
  - Index card files (Box 248)
    - Alphabetical index to Supreme Court cases
    - Calling card file (Box 249)
    - Index to speeches and writings (Box 250)
- Photographs, 1908-1973 (Box 251-256)
  Photographs, albums, and a photographic plate.
  Arranged by name of person, topic, or type of material.
  - Jackson, Robert H. (Box 251)
    - Early childhood to 1954 and undated See also Oversize, (10 folders)
    - Family members, 1921-1939 (Box 252)
    - Personal photographs taken or collected during Nuremberg War Crimes Trial, (2 folders)
    - Miscellany
      - Autographed photographs of friends
      - Bohemian Club
      - Jamestown, N.Y.
      - Miscellany
      - Outing at Camp Genesee, N.Y.
      - Postcards of Albany, N.Y.
  - Nuremberg War Crimes Trial (Box 253)
    - Pretrial
      - Inspection trip, July 1945
      - Jail courtroom, opera house, 8 July 1945
      - London, England, signing
      - Paris, France, office
      - Sessions
    - Trial
      - Courtroom scenes
        - General, (3 folders)
        - Defense counsel, (2 folders)
        - Prosecution tables
        - Prosecutions (American, British, French, Russian), (4 folders)
        - Speakers' stands (American, British, French, German, Russian), (5 folders)
        - Tribunal See also Oversize, (2 folders)
        - Visitors' gallery, (2 folders)
        - Witness stand
      - Defendants, group and individuals, (24 folders) (Box 254)
      - Evidence, (2 folders)
      - Grand Hotel, Nuremberg, Germany
      - Interpreters
      - Jackson, Robert H.
      - Judgment day (before sentencing)
      - Palace of Justice, Nuremberg, Germany See also Oversize, (2 folders) (Box 255)
      - Personnel
      - Personalities
      - Press activities
      - Press section
      - Prison
      - Social gatherings, (2 folders)
      - Witnesses
      - Unsorted
    - Volume of photographs by Charles Alexander (Box 256)
- Additions, 1940-1955 (Box 257-259)
  - Addition I, 1940-1946 (Box 257)
    Correspondence, will, statement, program, and a facsimile of a book.
    Arranged alphabetically by type of material and therein chronologically according to the arrangement of the main portion of the papers.
    - Family papers (Box 257)
      - Other papers
        - Craighill, Mary (Jackson) Loftus, 1946
    - Legal file
      - Nuremberg War Crimes Trial
        - Office files, United States chief of counsel
          - Hitler, Adolph, typescript translation of will, 1945
          - Speeches
            - Jackson's opening speech
              - German edition, 1945
              - Typescript, 1945
    - Miscellany
      - Programs and souvenirs, 1940
  - Addition II, 1955 (Box 258-259)
    An oral history transcript documenting reminiscences of Jackson's life.
    Arranged numerically by part.
    - Oral history transcript, "The Reminiscences of Robert H. Jackson," based on interviews by Harlan B. Phillips, 1955 See also Containers 190-191, "Justice Jackson's Story" (Box 258)
      - Parts I-V, (5 folders)
      - Parts VI-VIII, (4 folders) (Box 259)
- Oversize, 1913-1954 (Box OV 1-OV 21)
  Oversize certificates of appointments and awards, degrees, plot drawings, photographs, and scrapbooks.
  Organized and described according to the series from which the items were removed. Scrapbooks constitute a separate grouping within the Oversize series.
  - Subject file (Box OV 1)
    - Commission on the Administration of Justice in New York, 1931 (Container 27)
  - Legal file
    - Assistant general counsel, Bureau of Internal Revenue
      - Appointment and resignation, 1934 (Container 66)
  - Financial papers
    - Jamestown property, Jamestown, N.Y., early deeds, etc. (Container 201)
  - Miscellany
    - Awards, certificates, honors, and tributes, 1913, 1934-1944 (Containers 208 - 209)
  - Scrapbooks, 1928-1954 (Box OV 2)
    - Vol. 1, 1928-1940
    - Vol. 2, 1931-1934 (Box OV 3)
    - Vol. 3, 1934-1936 (Box OV 4)
    - Vol. 4, 1935 (Box OV 5)
    - Vol. 5, 1935-1936 (Box OV 6)
    - Vol. 6, 1935-1936 (Box OV 7)
    - Vol. 7, 1936-1937 (Box OV 8)
    - Vol. 8, 1937-1940 (Box OV 9)
    - Vol. 9, 1941 (Box OV 10)
    - Vol. 10, 1941 (Box OV 11)
    - Vol. 11, 1941-1943 (Box OV 12)
    - Vol. 12, 1943-1944 (Box OV 13)
    - Vol. 13, 1945 (Box OV 14)
    - Vol. 14, 1945 (Box OV 15)
    - Vol. 15, 1945 (Box OV 16)
    - Vol. 16, 1945-1946 (Box OV 17)
    - Vol. 17, 1946 (Box OV 18)
    - Vol. 18, 1954 (Box OV 19)
    - Vol. 19, "Struggle for Judicial Supremacy" (contains correspondence and book reviews) (Box OV 20)
  - Photographs (Box OV 21)
    - Jackson, Robert H.
      - Early childhood to 1954, 1938-1941, undated (Container 251)
    - Nuremberg War Crimes Trial
      - Trial
        - Courtroom scenes
          - Tribunal, 1945-1946 (Container 253)
        - Palace of Justice, undated (Container 255)
- Classified, 1952 (Box CL 1)
  One document containing national security information.
  Arranged according to the series, folder, and container from which the item was removed.
  - Legal file (Box CL 1)
    - Supreme Court
      - October term 1951
        - Miscellaneous correspondence and papers, 1952